我明白你的意思了  安迪
You've made your point, Andy.
就算他们关闭了机工车间
So they closed the machine shop
要改造成咖啡店
and turned it into an espresso bar.
并不代表你是糟糕的供应商
That doesn't make you a bad provider.
听着  别犯傻了  这里可是东河
Look, this is crazy. It's the East River.
你在这里只会挨冻患上感冒
The only thing you're gonna catch out here is a cold.
来了
Ooh.
噢  我的天啊
Oh, my god.
你能相信吗  我的旧校服竟然还合身
Can you believe my old grade school shirt still fits?
哪有合身啊  明明是紧身衣
Oh, like a glove, yes. A shirt, no.
你穿着好象绿巨人[漫画人物]
You look like the Incredible Hulk.
敢开我玩笑  老爸
Nice, dad.
在他埋头写书时
Yeah, that's what you get
跟他说话  都只会招他讥讽
when you talk to him while he's writing.
不过  格雷西一定会乐死
Mm. Well, Gracie's gonna love it.
-她要看见了  肯定会笑个不停  -格雷西
- It'll crack her up when she sees it. - Gracie?
那个举家搬离纽约的娇小可爱的娃啊
Little cutie whose family moved off to--
-是去了堪萨斯州吧  -在升五年级后
- I want to say Kansas? - After fifth grade.
她发邮件给我说要来市里考纽约时装学院
She e-mailed me she was coming to town to check out F.I.T.,
所以我就叫她来我家过夜
so I told her she could spend the night.
我问过你了
I asked you.
在我写书的时候吗
Was I writing?
怎么写了"绿巨人"
"Incredible Hulk"?
格雷西
Gracie!
你看你  还是青葱少女耶
Look at you, greendale girl.
看你  变化真大啊
L-look at you.
-好久不见  -好久不见
- Hi. - Hi.
还记得我奶奶和我爸吧
Uh, you remember gram and my dad.
当然  真是好久不见了啊
Sure. Hey. It's been forever.
-谢谢你们让我这里借宿  -哪里
- Thanks again for letting me crash with you guys. - Yeah.
你没换房间吧
So your room in the same place?
对啊  老地方  旧房间
Yeah. Same place, same old room.
什么都没变  几乎都没变
You know, everything the same. Almost.
看来某人早已不是那个堪萨斯少女了
Looks like someone's not in Kansas anymore.
当初那个扎着马尾  穿着中统袜的
What happened to the little hair band,
小女孩去哪了
the knee socks?
喂  贝克特  打来得真及时
Ah, Beckett. Excellent timing.
她以前很讨人喜欢的
She used to be so adorable.
我意思是  一个好女孩怎会...
I mean, what makes a girl--
那个过去玩"跳房子"游戏
a little girl who used to play hopscotch
骑我的小马的女孩
and my little ponies--
怎会突然就穿了眉环呢
suddenly pierce her eyebrow?
就像是她被皮装君主
It's like she's been assimilated
同化了似的
by the leather overlords.
也许是你把人幻想化了
You're probably romanticizing it.
不见得小学时代的事
And is anything ever really
就真的像我们所记得的那样
the way that we remember it in grade school?
坦白说
Well, to be honest,
除了那些小苏打火山
beyond some baking soda volcanoes
以及掌心老冒汗
and sweaty palms,
我基本把小学的事都忘了
I have very little memory of it at all.
你呢
You?
我只记得自己矫过牙
Mine are mostly orthodontic.
牙套妹啊
Braces?
原来你不是天生就笑容炫目的啊
You mean you weren't born with that dazzling smile?
唯一让我父母炫目的是
The only thing dazzling was how long
长时间为了矫牙掏腰包
it took my parents to pay for it.
这具浮尸基本上没有腐烂
Body's in pretty good shape for a floater.
一定是刚被投河不久
Must not have been in the water too long.
要是河水冷得跟我鼻子一样
Well, if the river's as cold as my nose,
我推断其死亡时间不超过12个小时
I'd ballpark it within the last 12 hours, at most.
没有身份证  但他看来是40岁出头
No I.D., but he looks early 40s.
他的手臂上有海军纹身
He's got a navy tattoo on his arm
颞线上有一道严重的挤压伤
and a nasty crush injury along his temporal line.
他会是翻船落水的吗
Any chance he went overboard?
种种迹象表明是人为的钝器伤
Classic indicators point to deliberate blunt force,
所以我看不是
so I'd say no.
他并非死于翻船事故
This was no boating accident.
那我们最好封锁海滨
Then we better close the beaches.
"并非死于翻船事故"
"No boating accident"?
知道布罗迪警长吗  那霍普尔呢
Chief Brody? Hooper?
不是没看过吧
Seriously?
我会将他的指纹发到辖区  查出他的身份
I'll, uh, zip his prints over to the precinct for an I.D.,
另外  不管有没有用  我找到了这个
but for what it's worth, I did find this.
匿名戒赌互助会奖章
A gamblers anonymous medallion.
要戒赌四年才能得到
Four years without a bet.
-啊  -你"啊"什么
- Ahh. - "Ahh," What?
死在东河  身上有匿名戒赌互助会币
The East River, a G.A. Chip?
复赌的赌徒欠了他的赌博经纪太多
Relapsed gambler gets in too deep with his bookie,
结果落得浮尸河里的下场
ends up floating in the drink.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
一下子就从匿名戒赌互助会跳到黑帮暗杀
You just went from gamblers anonymous to mob hit?
这可是泽西湿地这边
This is the most celebrated body depository
最经典的弃尸手法啊
this side of the Jersey wetlands.
听我的错不了  这家伙与黑帮有关
Mark my words-- this guy has mob ties.
结案了
Case closed.
他和黑帮无关
No mob ties.
你查清楚了吗
Are you sure?
做得好
Good work.
根据指纹查询结果  他名叫唐纳德·海耶斯
According to his fingerprints, his name is Donald Hayes--
是退役海军  曾参与"沙漠风暴"行动
Navy veteran, served in Desert Storm,
沙漠风暴指1990年以美国为首的多国部队针对伊拉克侵占科威特
而发动的军事进攻
94年后开始在码头打工
and he's been a dock worker since '94.
不知怎的  他人仍在上班
And somehow still employed as one.
本案的死者唐尼·海耶斯
Our victim Donny Hayes--
目前正在东河码头打卡上班
currently clocked in and on duty at the East Side docks.
也就是说
Which either means
他是一具很热爱工作的僵尸
he's an incredibly dedicated zombie...
又或者是本起谋杀案的疑犯
Or he's a suspect in our murder.
唐尼
Donny.
海耶斯先生
Mr. Hayes.
唐纳德·海耶斯
Donald Hayes.
你是怎么了  忘了自己的名字了吗
What's the matter? You forget your own name?
警察  别跑
Police. Don't move.
我拍档不是说"别跑"嘛
The man said, "Don't move."
噢  等一下
Oh. Wait a minute.
等等  你们只是警察而已吗
Wait a minute. You're just cops?
警察而已
Just cops?
照你这么说  你不过也就是因涉嫌谋杀被捕"而已"
I guess that makes you just under arrest for murder.
名为格兰特  姓维罗
First name Grant, Last name Vyro.
我可没杀人
I didn't kill anybody.
-那你干嘛跑啊  -我以为你们是工会的人
- Then why'd you run? - I thought you was with union.
这么说不只是我们在追查
Oh, so we're not the only ones who have a problem
你为了夺取工会卡而杀了唐尼这件事啊
with you killing Donny for his union card?
你在说什么  那卡是我买的
What are you talking about? I bought that card.
你真的以为我们会相信
Do you really expect us to believe
你只是买了唐尼的卡  偷了他的身份
that you bought Donny's card, assumed his identity,
自以为神不知鬼不觉吗
and thought no one would notice?
这家伙在曼哈顿西区工作了16年
Guy spent 16 years working over on the West Side.
所以我才转来东区的码头打工
So I switched to the east side docks
那样认识唐尼的人就不会发现
so no one who knew Donny would catch on.
自从购买他人工会卡视为犯法后
So what does a union card go for nowadays
今时今日一张工会卡要多少钱啊
since buying someone else's is illegal?
-花了我两万五千美元  -少扯了  维罗
- Sucker cost me 25 grand. - Oh, come on, Vyro.
码头工每年有超过6位数的进账
Dock workers rake in over six figures a year.
唐尼怎会愿意把卡贱卖给你
Why would Donny trade it in for so little?
除非你拿枪抵着他的头
Unless he had a gun to his head,
-所以他才能讨价还价  -我哪来的枪啊
- in which case, it'd be a bargain. - There were no guns.
-我要找工作  唐尼要现金  -要来做什么
- I needed a job. Donny needed cash. - For what?
他没说  我也不在乎
He didn't say, and I didn't care.
我说他的头部遭钝器所伤是对的
I was right about the blunt force trauma.
一记重击狠狠砸在
A single blow caved in the ridge here
鳞缝上的脑脊这里
along Donny's squamosal suture.
不管凶器是什么  它在死者的头骨里
And whatever did the damage was kind enough
留下了这块红色玻璃碎片
to leave this shard of red glass embedded in his skull.
会是一个大花瓶或大玻璃瓶吗
Maybe a heavy vase or a bottle?
我会让鉴证组查一下的
I'll have forensics take a look at it,
看能不能找到匹配的凶器
see if they can find a match.
根据尸斑和水温
Based on lividity and water temp,
我把死亡时间缩窄在
I've narrowed time of death
今早凌晨4点到6点之间
to between 4:00 and 6:00 a.m. this morning.
-肩膀这伤是怎么造成的  -大号铅弹
- What happened here on the shoulder? - Buckshot.
我在他的左臂找到几颗
I found several double-ought pellets
卡在肉里的点33口径铅弹
lodged in the flesh of his left arm.
就是说有人重击他的头部  然后朝他开了枪
So someone conked him on the head and shot him?
怪就怪在这儿了  伤疤表明
That's where it gets weird. Scarring indicates
铅块在他体内已经两三周了
The pellets have been there about two to three weeks.
他就这么留着不管
And he just left 'em in there?
反正他没去就医
Well, he certainly didn't seek treatment.
也许他卷入了什么非法勾当
Could've been, he was in something illegal
-或者是害怕那个枪击他的人  -或者两者皆是
- Or scared of whoever shot him.  - Or both.
可以排除维罗了
Forget Vyro.
他的不在场证明成立  我们查到
His alibi cleared, and we tracked down
有张两万五千美元的私人支票
his personal check for $25,000,
上个月被唐尼存入了个人账户
endorsed and deposited by Donny last month.
维罗付给唐尼一张支票
Vyro paid Donny with a check?
不够"黑帮"吗  卡塞尔
Not mobby enough for you, Castle?
鉴证组还在检查唐尼的住处
CSU's still combing Donny's place,
但没发现红色玻璃的碎片
but no broken red glass,
也没有跟谋杀相关的线索
no signs of foul play,
也没发现亲属
and no next of kin, either.
那个匿名戒赌互助会的奖章呢
What about the gamblers anonymous chip?
-查到保证人 了吗  -查到了
- Any sponsor? - Yeah, but he
但他说几个月没有唐尼的消息了
says he hasn't heard from Donny for months.
所以卡塞尔也许是对的
So then maybe castle was right.
如果唐尼走投无路到变卖他的工会卡
If Donny was desperate enough to sell his union card,
那他也许真是赌瘾复发
then maybe he fell off the wagon and
欠了一屁股债
got in over his head.
是啊  两万五可不是小数目
Yeah, to the tune of 25 grand.
伙计们  那是虚报的金额
Yo. Uh, that'd be lowballing it, bro.
唐尼的户头显示  他一个月前
Donny's account shows that he deposited Vyro's check
存入了维罗的支票
about a month ago,
外加他的个人存款中
adding it to his existing balance
12万5千美元
of $125,000,
而这些钱  看好了
All of which--wait for it--
现在都没了
is now gone.
-没了  -全部吗
- Gone?  - All of it?
只剩了6美元23美分
Except for the remaining balance of $6.23,
其余的十五万都换成了一张大额支票
all the 150k was spent in one giant check,
付给了一个叫做威尔伯·皮特里诺的人
made payable to a Wilbur Pittorino,
这里显示此人拥有多处不动产
Listed here as owning several properties,
其中一项是废物处理业务
as well as a waste management business
厂址在新泽西的加菲尔德
in Garfield, New Jersey.
废物处理业务
Oh! Waste management.
-有前科吗  -有
- Any priors?  - Yeah.
1977年  比利·皮特在联邦监狱坐了十年牢
Back in 1977, Billy Pitt spent 10 years in federal
罪名是非法袭击他人和敲诈勒索
for assault and racketeering.
-和啥  -敲诈勒索
- And what?  - Racketeering.
他还在进行他的外围下注操作的地方
As well as shaking down business owners
勒索了一些企业业主
where he operated his, uh, bookmaking operation.
-他的啥  -外围下注操作
- His what now?  - Bookmaking operation.
哦  这么说  一个前赌徒
Oh, so an ex-gambler
把毕生的积蓄交给了一个搞外围下注的前科犯
dumps his life savings on an ex-con ex-bookmaker,
最后却被清理出局了
and ends up exed out.
听起来像是唐尼还给比利·皮特的十五万付晚了
Sounds like Donny was late with his 150 grand for Billy Pitt,
最终只能以生命来还债了
and he ended up paying for it with his life.
我说的不就这意思么
I think I just said that.
翻译：小池 苏小黛 深深 大卫熊 千花 小易 小蛮腰
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳  小猫   后期：瓜瓜   校对：大卫熊   总监：安小七
皮特先生  您的头发可能白了一些
You know, you might have gotten a little grayer, Mr. Pitt,
但在我看来  您并无太大变化
but it seems to me, you haven't changed much at all.
肯定是上普拉提课的功劳
Must be all them pilates classes.
你认得这张支票吗
Do you recognize this check?
当然  唐尼·海耶斯给的  有何问题
Of course. It's from Donny Hayes. So?
我在想  如果唐尼没欠你那么多钱
So I'm wondering if Donny didn't owe you more money,
你也没回到过去敲诈勒索的日子
and you didn't flash back to your old racketeering days.
等等  美女
Tap the brakes, sweetie.
不管你把我找来所为何事
Whatever the hell you dragged me down here for,
我现在就可以告诉你
I wanna tell you right now that
我几辈子前就跟强尼·劳两清了
I paid my tab with Johnny Law a couple of lifetimes ago,
他后来再也没逮到过我
and he's got nothing on me since.
赞  这人太经典了
Oh, this guy is gold.
你要是不信我  不如去问问...唐尼
And if you don't believe me, why don't you ask... Donny?
唐尼出事了是吗
Is this about donny?
今早在纽约东河  有人发现了他的尸体
He was found dead in the east river this morning.
现在回到钱的问题上  这钱到底是干什么的
Now back to the money. What was it for?
是还款  还是礼物
Was it a payment or was it a gift?
-是买卖  -买什么
- A purchase. - For?
他买了我在市中心的酒吧  他喜欢那地方
He bought my bar downtown. He loved the place.
是吗  喜欢到舍弃了一切
Really? Enough to drop everything
并为之倾尽了毕生的积蓄吗
and dump his whole life savings into it?
那孩子是在那长大的
Kid was practically raised in the joint,
他的外公抚养了他  传奇里奥
by his grandfather, Leo the legend.
-传奇里奥  -你听说过
- Leo the legend?  - You heard of the guy?
他是城里最好的酒保
City's best bartender
当时"基佬"只有"快乐"的意思
since the days when "Gay" meant "Happy."
他是唐尼唯一的亲人
He was the only father Donny knew.
在哪能找到里奥
And where do I find Leo?
他在酒吧后面的银色调酒罐里安息着呢
Resting in an old silver shaker behind the bar.
里奥算是"酒吧历史学家"了
Leo was kind of the bar historian,
97年他被开除后
and when he kicked in '97,
我们想  何不拉他入伙呢
we figured, hey, why not make him part of it?
酒吧后的骨灰
Ashes behind the bar.
所以唐尼才决定买下  酒吧叫什么名字
Which is why Donny decided to buy the--what is it called?
-"老地方"  -"老地方"
- The old haunt.  - The old haunt?
别告诉我你们没去过那个地方
Don't tell me you've never been to the old haunt.
那是传奇啊  所有的好作家都在那喝酒
It's legendary. All the great writers drank there.
-咱是警察  咱有警察常去的酒吧  -遗憾啊
- We're cops. We go to cop bars.  - Your loss.
总之  唐尼每晚都在那里
Donny was there every night anyhow.
我们是他唯一的亲人了
We were all the family he had.
那这次突然的买卖是怎么回事
So what prompted this sudden sale?
貌似唐尼需要在很短的时间内筹够钱才行
I mean, it seemed like Donny had to gather money pretty quickly.
酒吧只赔不赚已经好几年了
The bar had been weighing down my ledger sheets for years.
本来TJ麦克查纳连锁店提出买我的酒吧
I had an offer from one of them T.J. Mcchucklenuts franchises,
不过我的酒保布莱恩  找了几个投资者
when Brian, my bartender, put together some investors
也提出想买我的酒吧
and made an offer of his own.
我本来就要卖给他了
I was gonna sell it to him,
结果唐尼出了更高的价格
and then donny outbid him.
那唐尼买下了酒吧  布莱恩做何感想
And how did Brian feel when donny bought the place?
他当然不太高兴
He wasn't thrilled about it,
但他起码不用为TJ麦克查纳工作了
But at least he wasn't working for T.J. Mcchucklenuts.
蕾妮检查了玻璃碎片
Lanie just swabbed the shard of glass
发现有微量酒精成分
and found trace amounts of alcohol.
一个装酒精饮料的瓶子
A container of alcoholic beverage,
一个充满怨恨的酒保
A resentful bartender...
而且考虑到"老地方"所处的位置
And given the location of the old haunt,
一个距离河边两个街区的潜在犯罪现场
a potential crime scene just two blocks
就呼之欲出了
away from the river.
实在是居家旅行  杀人灭口  必备场所
Convenient for all your body dumping needs.
我说  卡塞尔
So, Castle...
要我请你喝一杯吗
Can I buy you a drink?
贝克特探长  我等你这句话等得花都谢了
Why, Detective Beckett, I thought you'd never ask.
你对这酒吧了解多少  卡塞尔
so how well do you know this bar, castle?
我好几年没来了  阿丽克西斯出生后就没来过
Oh, I haven't been here in years. Not since Alexis.
不过我的第一本小说就是在这里写出来的
But I wrote most of my first novel in one of these booths.
原来如此  难怪了
Oh. Okay, well, that explains a lot.
那小说卖出了三百多万本
It sold over three million copies.
我是说  故地重游  难怪你这么激动
No, I mean why you're so excited.
这里可承载着历史啊
Oh, well, it's loaded with history--
最初是个铁匠铺  后来变成了妓院
First as a blacksmith, then as a bordello.
它在禁酒令期间成为地下酒吧
It only became a bar during prohibition as a speakeasy,
一度是最好的酒吧之一
and it was one of the best.
我发誓  我现在仍能感受到
I swear, I can still feel the vibration
这些墙里沉淀着的
of every notorious episode of glamour and debauchery
魅惑和堕落
in its walls.
别激动  卡塞尔  只是个酒吧
Oh, easy, Castle. It's just a bar.
不  TJ麦克查纳才只是个酒吧
No, no, T.J. Mcchucklenuts is just a bar.
"老地方"可是酒吧界濒临绝种的
The old haunt is the last of a dying breed
稀有圣地
of proud institutions
笑看着城市变得越来越高级  越来越无情
standing up to ruthless gentrification.
它是个经典的...
It's a classic...
你  你干嘛
What--what are you doing?
我要找布莱恩套话
Well, I'm not gonna get much out of Brian
可不能弄个警察造型
looking like a cop.
隐藏身份  我喜欢
Undercover. I like it.
不过保险起见  最好再开一颗扣子
But you might want to pop one more button, just in case.
-酒吧就该是这个味儿  -是啊  陈啤酒
- This is how a bar should smell.  - Yeah. Stale beer.
知道吗  要是多几家这样的酒吧
You know, I'd write in more bars
我就不用偏偏跑到这里写作了
if there were more bars like this.
你好啊  艾迪
Nice to see you, Eddie.
好久不见  多谢你还记得我
Been a long time. Thank you for remembering.
过来  来看看名人墙
Come over here. Check out the wall of fame.
这位帅哥是谁啊  在海明威上面两排
Who is that handsome devil just two over from Hemingway,
就在那个我写出《枪林弹雨中》的
directly above the infamous booth where
隔间的正上方
"In a hail of bullets" was born?
哦买糕啊  卡塞尔
Oh, my goodness, castle.
你以前好可爱啊
you were so cute back then.
现在不可爱吗
Back then?
充满回忆啊
A lot of memories.
那是老里奥的骨灰  那个小孩就应该是唐尼
That's old Leo, which would make that young Donny.
但我没看到有红色酒瓶啊
But I don't see any red bottles.
你在看什么呢
What are you looking at?
没什么
Nothing.
欢迎光临"老地方"  朋友们
Welcome to the Old Haunt, folks.
唐尼在吗
Uh, is Donny here, by any chance?
不在  不过一会儿就到了  他绝对不会
Not yet, but he will be, and he won't mind one bit
介意你坐了他一贯的位子的
that you're sitting in his regular spot.
怪不得  我一坐这儿就觉得很亲切
You know, I knew this place felt right for a reason.
我叫凯特  是他一个老朋友
I'm Kate. I'm one of his old friends.
这位是里克
And this is Rick.
我是布莱恩
Brian.
唐尼的朋友
And any old friend of Donny
也就是我的朋友
is a new friend of mine.
请问一下  布莱恩
Tell me, Brian, um...
你们这儿有没有一种烈酒
You don't by any chance carry a liqueur--
口感醇厚
It's really delicious
而且是用红色酒瓶装着
and it comes in this red bottle?
对了  是我们在火地岛的小酒馆
Yeah, that, uh, red bottle we shared
喝的那种用红色瓶子装的酒吗
down in that little cantina in Tierra del Fuego?
红色是吧
Red, huh?
让我找找
Uh, let's see.
没红色的  只有常见的棕色  绿色和透明的
No red here. Just your standard brown, green, and clear.
-我去那边找找  -你看到没
- Uh, let me check the other end of the bar.  - Did you see that?
怎么可能没看到  难道他不知道我们是一对儿吗
How could I miss it? Can't he see we're together?
我们的卧底身份
Undercover.
不是说那个  是他的反应
No, his reaction...
当我提到唐尼的时候
When I mentioned Donny.
他好像不知道
I don't think he knows.
也许他很擅长掩饰
Maybe he's just a good liar.
没找到啊
Ah, no luck.
要不要试下蓝伏特加
Maybe I could interest you in a blue vodka?
哦  不用了  还不到喝那个的时候呢
Oh, no, thank you. Way too early for vodka.
先考虑下吧  朋友们  我马上回来
Well, think about it, folks. I'll be back in a sec.
事实上  布莱恩  我们不是来喝酒的
Actually, Brian, we're not really here for a drink.
唐尼怎么可能死了呢
How could Donny be dead?
我昨晚还跟他在一起
I was just with him last night.
什么时候
What time was that?
凌晨四点半  我下班时把门锁上了
4:30 a.m. I locked up on my way out,
唐尼和往常一样到办公室去整理账单去了
and Donny went to do the books in the office, like always.
你确定你走的时候他是一个人吗
Are you sure he was alone when you left?
确定无疑  这简直太不可思议了
Positive. Man, this is crazy.
他跟我情同兄弟
That guy was like a brother to me.
尽管他买下了你也想买的这个酒吧
Even though he bought the bar out from under you?
你知道这件事
You know about that?
他甚至没提议让你入股合伙
I mean, he didn't even offer you to be a partner.
这可不像兄弟会做的事啊
That doesn't sound very brotherly to me.
我和唐尼之间没有隔夜仇的
Hey, any beef I had with Donny was short-lived.
我们总能尽快和解
We hashed it out.
这么说你现在不过是从他那儿偷东西而已
So now you're just stealing from him.
-什么  -什么
- What?  - What?
一不小心看穿了你的小把戏  布莱恩
Couldn't help but notice your trick with the fruit, Brian.
你假装在收酒钱
You pretend to ring up a drink,
把钱放到收银箱里面  暗中却
you stuff the money in the till, and you keep track of it
把水果扔进清洗槽里  以此来记录钱的数目
by throwing pieces of fruit into the sink.
樱桃代表10美元  清柠代表20美元吗
Cherries are $10. Limes, what, $20?
到下班的时候  清点下水果数
At night's end, you tally up your fruit so you know how much
就知道该拿多少小费了
to put into your tip cup before you lock the register.
到底发生了什么呢  布莱恩
So what happened, Brian?
是被唐尼抓现行了吗
Donny catch you stealing?
然后一场恶战不可避免
Things get physical?
就为了那三四十美元吗
Over an extra 30 or 40 bucks?
那不叫偷  是赚点油水  唐尼很大度的
That's not even stealing. It's skimming. Donny understood.
店主很大度吗
The owner understood?
我们像一家人一样  很长时间了
We'd all been family long enough.
唐尼知道我有时候为了钱交房租
Donny knew I had to get creative to make my rent
会搞点小手段
once in a while.
我想看下他的办公室
I'd like to see his office.
可以  在地下室
Sure. It's in the basement.
地下室
The basement?
我从来没看到过
I've never seen this.
在98年洪水之前都没人知道这个地方
No one knew it was there until the flood of '98.
比利·皮特掀开油毯
Billy Pitt pulled up the old linoleum,
才发现了它
and there it was.
秘密地下室
A hidden basement.
这可太酷了
How cool is this?
我刚说的"酷"吗
Did I say "Cool"?
应该说是"令人惊叹"
Make that awesome.
谋杀的绝好地点
The perfect place for a murder.
没人能听到呼救声
No one can hear you scream.
但也没人能帮忙搬尸体
No one can help you carry the body up the stairs either.
也许是有人拿枪一直押着唐尼
Maybe somebody marched Donny at gunpoint
到了河边  在那儿才杀了他
down to the river, killed him there.
若凶手有枪的话  为什么还用瓶子呢
If the killer had a gun, why would he use a bottle?
别拿逻辑来分析我的故事
Don't ruin my story with your logic.
刚刚漆过的油漆味儿
It smells like fresh paint.
是的   唐尼花了很多时间
Yeah, Donny had been putting in a lot of work
来打点这里  装了新黄铜栏杆
to fix the place up-- new brass rail,
翻新酒吧的木板
refurbished wood on the bar.
发现什么了吗
You find something?
这儿有铅弹弹洞
These are buckshot holes.
你有猎枪吗  布莱恩
You own a shotgun, Brian?
-没有  -鉴证组会对这里进行仔细检查
- No. - CSU's gonna comb this place from top to bottom--
血迹  铅弹  碎红色玻璃
Blood, buckshot, broken red glass.
-如果你知道些什么的话  -听我说
- So if you have something to say--  - Look,
若有人在这里开猎枪的话
if a shotgun was fired down here,
酒吧所有的人都会知道
everybody in the bar would know about it.
打烊之后呢
Not if it was after hours.
我是说两到三星期前
We're talking about two or three weeks ago.
那时候唐尼和谁有过过节吗
Did Donny have a beef with anyone then?
你说两星期前
You said two weeks ago?
是的
Uh, yeah.
两星期前  我正在收拾准备下班
It was a couple of weeks ago. I was, uh, closing up alone.
我把钱拿到地下室保险箱放好
I had just done my cash drop down in the basement safe,
刚一上来  就听到有人在敲门
and I came up, and some guy was knocking on the door--
是皮卡皮特
Pick-up Pete.
"搭讪"皮特  因为他喜欢受女性欢迎吗
"Pick-up Pete"? Big hit with the ladies?
不是  他开一辆皮卡
No. He drives a pickup.
闹事鬼
Gun rack?
是的  一个乡巴佬常客
Yeah. Regular upstate redneck.
总之  他说把钱包忘在隔间了
Anyway, he said that he dropped his wallet in the booth,
我就让他进来了
So I let him in.
结果呢  他对我动手动脚的
Next thing you know, he's got his hands all over me.
他把我压向吧台  突然
He's pushing me against the bar. All of a sudden,
地下室的门开了
the basement door pops open,
唐尼走了出来  像海明威的鬼魂一样
and here comes Donny, like Hemingway's ghost.
估计是我之前没看到他
Guess I missed him down there,
不过我很高兴他出现了
but I'm glad he showed up when he did.
他拿了根棒球棒  把皮特赶出去了
He grabbed a baseball bat, chased Pete out.
在那混蛋开车离开之前
He smashed his taillights,
他打烂了他的尾灯
put a few dents in the pickup for good measure
还把车身打了几个凹痕
before the jackass could drive off.
唐尼让我回家  并忘了这事儿
Donny told me to go home and to forget about it.
他说皮特永远也来不了这个酒吧了
He said that Pete was eighty-sixed for life.
自那以后我们再没谈过那件事了
That was the last time we talked about it
直到昨天晚上
until last night.
-昨晚发生了什么  -皮特又来了
- And what happened last night?  - Pete showed up again.
唐尼忍无可忍  直接把他赶了出去
Donny wasn't having any of it. He just threw that trash out.
还说再有下次
Said the next time,
挨打的就不是那辆车了
it wouldn't be the truck he used the bat on.
也就是说唐尼给皮特下了禁令
So Donny eighty-sixed Pete for life.
而皮特则来了个"礼尚往来"
Looks like Pete returned the favor.
皮卡皮特  又叫皮特·穆夏
Pick-up Pete, A.K.A. Pete Mucha.
有几项被驳回的家庭暴力指控
He's got a couple of dismissed domestic assault charges
而且还是一把
and he is also the proud owner
雷明顿870猎枪的所有者
of a remington 870 shotgun.
莱恩和埃斯波西托正带他过来呢
And Ryan and Esposito are bringing him in now.
你觉得"卡塞骏马"这名字怎么样
What do you think of "The Castillion"?
干什么的
For?
"老地方"刚好提醒了我
Well, the Old Haunt just reminded me
酒馆文化对这个城市有着多么重大的意义
of how vital tavern culture is in this town.
我想  何不自己开个酒馆呢
I thought, why not open up a little tavern of my own?
你是说现成的酒吧不去
So instead of buying a drink,
非要买下一个才甘心
you're gonna buy a whole bar?
这是我回报的方式
My way of giving back.
-是啊  回报给你的自负还差不多  -"自负吧"
- Yeah, to your ego. - "The ego."
快报警
Someone call the police!
放开我  我挺好的
Let me go. I'm perfectly fine!
我猜他是皮卡皮特
Pick-up Pete, I take it.
是的  我发现他在市中心的酒吧被踢了出来
Yeah, we found him getting tossed out of a bar uptown.
还有  跟他车里的猎枪一样
And, uh, just like the shotgun in his truck,
他喝醉了[loaded还有上膛的意思]
he's a little loaded.
也许谋杀的指控能让他清醒清醒
Well, maybe a murder charge will sober him up.
是啊  来吧
Yeah. Come on.
"城堡"[卡塞尔的名字有城堡的意思]
"The Castle."
刚好可以弄个小吊桥  踏着走进酒吧
It'll just have a wee drawbridge to let you in.
恭喜你  皮特
Congratulations, Pete.
你是我们今年最烂醉如泥的谋杀嫌疑犯
You're our drunkest murder suspect this year,
-可是包括圣帕特里克节那天哦  -奖品是什么
- and that includes St. Patrick's day. - What did I win?
-看你的表现了  皮特  -你知道我叫什么
- Well, that depends on you, Pete. - You know my name.
你刚刚提到"谋杀"了吗
And did you just say "Murder"?
你的驾照上注明你住在科克兰
Your driver's license says you're from up in Cortland.
怎么  那里没有酒吧吗
What, they don't have any bars up there,
还是你在那的酒吧也被人下了禁令
or did you get eighty-sixed from them, too?
城里是我工作的地方
The city's where I work,
铺预制墙板啊  铺管道啊
you know, like drywall, like pipe setting.
我在下班之后管道铺的最好了[暗指性交]
And I do some of my best pipe laying after work,
你们懂的
if you know what I mean.
你拥有一把猎枪  皮特
You own a shotgun, Pete.
你喜欢打猎  是吗
You like hunting, do you?
等等
Wait a minute.
你们因为我打死一只鹿说我谋杀吗
You after me for murdering a 2-point buck?
不是  我们是因为你两周前
Nah. We're after you for your little dust up
在"老地方"那闹事抓你
at the old haunt two weeks ago.
"老地方"  我昨晚就在那啊
The old haunt! That's where I was last night.
唐尼就因为那个婊子酒保
Donny wouldn't let me in
不让我进去
because of that bitch bartender.
我要声明一下  是她主动勾搭我的
For the record, she came on to me.
那就是你回到那里  杀死他的原因吗
That why you came back and you killed him,
因为你喝醉了  暴怒
'cause you were drunk and angry,
他不让你进去吗
and he wouldn't let you in?
唐尼死了
Donny's dead?
你昨晚到底干了什么  皮特
What'd you really do last night, Pete?
喂  等等
Whoa! Hey!
我杀他干什么
Why would I kill the guy?
因为他把你的车砸坏了
Maybe because he trashed your truck.
而且你上次拿着猎枪向他射击的时候
And you were too drunk to shoot straight
你酒喝得太多  根本就没发准确的打中他
the last time you came after him with a shotgun.
猎枪
Shotgun?
听着  他的确砸坏了我的车  那又如何
Look, he trashed my truck. So what?
他付的钱比车造成的损毁多得多
He more than paid for the damages.
他干什么了
He what now?
在他砸坏我的车之后  我就要报警
After he pounded my truck, I started calling the cops.
他立马就冷静了下来  拿出厚厚一沓钱
Well, he calmed down real fast, and out came this fat wad,
从里面拿出了一千美元  一点都不心疼
and he peeled off a cool grand like it was nothin'.
唐尼...给了你一千美元
Donny... gave you $1,000?
他还有好多呢
He had plenty more.
我问他"你中彩票了吗"
I asked him, "What, did you score lotto?"
他回答说"差不多吧"
And he was all like, "Yeah, sorta."
你可以问问给我修车的那个人
You can ask my repair guy.
我用唐尼给我的现金付的帐
I paid with Donny's cash.
坐着别动  我去打个电话
Don't go anywhere. I'm gonna make a call.
别急  我们会抓到他的
Don't worry. We're gonna get this guy.
皮特的不在场证明成立
Pete's alibi holds.
他在穆雷山
He was sleeping it off
一个朋友家睡大觉
at a friend's apartment over in Murray Hill.
奇怪的是  银行账户只剩六元二十三美分的人
It's weird that a guy who had only $6.23 in his bank account
竟然可以毫不犹豫的拿出一千美元
had enough cash on hand to peel off a "G" like it was nothing.
更别提酒吧的那些装修费用了
Not to mention all the repairs he made to the bar.
也许他也在揩油
Maybe he was skimming, too.
如果他揩油揩到那种程度
If he was skimming that much,
他肯定会欠某人钱的
there'd have to be someone he wasn't paying--
供货商或是经销商
A supplier, distributor?
你们再去一趟"老地方"
Why don't you guys go back to the old haunt
查查唐尼的账簿
and take a look at Donny's ledgers?
找找那笔钱是从哪来的
Let's find out where that money was coming from.
给你  探长
Here you go, Detective.
谢谢
Thank you.
鉴证组检查了酒吧和地下室
So CSU processed that bar and basement,
没有找到任何破碎的红色玻璃
and there's no indication of any broken red glass.
而找到的唯一的血迹是在铅弹上
And the only blood they found was under the buckshot.
这么说那里不是凶案现场
So it wasn't our murder scene.
看起来唐尼离开酒吧的时候还活着
Well, looks like Donny left that bar alive.
有一点我不明白
You know, I don't get it.
如果唐尼在这里被击中
If Donny got shot down here,
他又没干坏事
and he didn't do anything wrong,
为什么不报警呢
Why didn't he report it?
新开张酒吧的业主最不希望的
The last thing any new bar owner wants
就是和条子有瓜葛
is trouble with the cops.
就算是一起意外枪击事件
Even an accidental shooting on the premises
都会使唐尼丢掉卖酒的执照
could've cost Donny his liquor license for good.
也许是因为这个原因
Oh, probably why he shelled out
-他才和皮特私了  -看不出来哪来的钱
- for pete's truck damage, too.  - I don't see how.
不光他的个人银行账户岌岌可危
His personal account isn't the only thing that's tapped out.
"老地方"勉强维持收支平衡
The old haunt was barely breaking even,
大多数时间是亏本经营
Operating at a loss most days.
他根本就不可能随便拿出钱来的
There's no way he was throwing money around.
但是他还是有钱的  这有发票
Yet, he was. I've got invoices here--
一张是黄铜栏杆
one for the new brass rail
还有一张是给酒吧新换的木板
and one for the new wood for the bar,
每张发票的价格都接近六千美元
Each totaling close to 6 grand.
两张都盖了"现金付款"和"已付全款"
Both of 'em are stamped "Petty cash. Paid in full."
真是出手大方啊
Nothing petty about that.
你确定那里面没有提到中彩票吗
You sure there's nothing in there about him winning the lotto?
事实上
Actually...
还真有
Maybe there is.
一张海根&格瑞姆拍卖行的寄售收据
A consignment receipt from Hagen & Graham auction house?
像唐尼这样的人怎么会和
Why is a guy like Donny doing business
卖毕加索和伦勃朗作品的地方扯上关系
with a place that sells Picassos and rembrandts?
他的生意勉强维持收支平衡
His business was barely breaking even.
他马上就要失去一切了
He was on the verge of losing everything.
工会卡也卖掉了
And with his union card gone,
看起来他又找到了其他的东西可卖
It looks like he found something else to sell.
是什么呢
Yeah, but what?
一个码头工人能有什么值钱的东西
What does a dock worker have that's valuable enough for
能够引起海根&格瑞姆拍卖行的兴趣呢
a place like Hagen & Graham's to be interested?
也许是不属于他的东西
Maybe something that wasn't his.
应该有个地方歌颂历史  推崇工艺
Now here's a place that honors history and values craftsmanship.
你对这些保留历史什么的很感兴趣  是吧
You're pretty into this whole preserving history stuff, huh?
只不过是最近我发现有些事情改变了
I think just lately, I've been noticing the changes.
你是说阿丽克西斯的哥特风朋友吗
You mean in Alexis' goth friend?
不  我是在想时代广场那个区域
No, I was thinking more along the lines of times square.
知道吗  那里曾经渗透着真正纽约的风情和质感
You know, once it had a real New York grit and character.
现在那个地方应该叫做时代广场那疙瘩
And now they should just call it times square land.
很抱歉让你们久等
So sorry to have kept you waiting.
我是史蒂芬·海斯勒  副董事
I'm Steven Heisler, associate director.
我是凯特·贝克特探长  这位是理查德·卡塞尔
I'm Detective Kate Beckett. This is Richard Castle.
我们想问问
We were wondering
-你是否记得这个人  -是的  唐纳德·海耶斯
- if you recognize this man.  - Oh, yes. Donald Hayes.
你想象的到  通常没有码头工人光顾这里
We don't get many dock workers here, as you might imagine.
有什么事
What's this about?
-他被谋杀了  -谋杀了  老天
- He was murdered.  - Murdered? Good lord.
我们了解到他拿了一个物品到这里拍卖
We understand that he put an item up here for auction.
我们想知道那是什么
We were wondering what it was.
你们认识一个叫做吉米·沃克的人吗
Are you familiar with a man by the name of Jimmy Walker?
当然  地球人都知道吉米·沃克[很多人叫这个名字]
Sure. Everybody knows Jimmy Walker.
不  不是在《欢乐时光》演小杰那个
No, not the actor who played JJ on "Good times."
当然不是  你说的是纽约的前任市长
No, the former mayor of New York.
1926年当选
Took office 1926,
昵称叫做"美男詹姆斯"
went by the nickname "Beau James,"
是个出了名的腐败政府官员  花花公子
famous for being a corrupt politician, renowned womanizer,
而且公开反对禁酒令
and also openly defiant of prohibition.
这么说  你的确知道他
Ah. So you do know him.
前任市长和我们的案子有什么关系
What does the former mayor have to do with this?
唐纳德拥有一件原本属于前任市长的东西
Donald had an item that once belonged to him.
是这样  传言说沃克市长
You see, Mayor Walker was rumored
拥有私人的酒品收藏  被认为
to have had a private liquor collection thought to contain
是蒸馏出来的最上等的威士忌
one of the finest whiskeys ever distilled.
当联邦特工把沃克赶出办公室时候
Unceremoniously dumped into the sewers
酒被随意的丢进了下水道
when federal agents ran Walker out of office.
唐纳德带着唯一幸存的酒 过来
Donald came in with the sole surviving bottle--
一八七五年的圣米里亚姆  极品威士忌
an 1875 St. Miriam, rock of Scotland.
我一看见蜡封上压印的J.W
I knew what it was the moment I saw
就知道这是什么了
the "J.W" Pressed into its wax seal.
一八七五年的圣米里亚姆
An 1875 St. Miriam--
这相当于威士忌中的圣杯
that is the holy grail of scotches.
只要能尝一口  我什么都肯做
I would kill for just a taste of that.
你有那瓶酒的照片吗
Do you have a picture of this bottle of scotch?
唐尼在哪里弄到这个的
Where did Donny get it?
他的爷爷里奥留给他的
Left to him by his grandfather Leo,
很显然这是他从第二次世界大战
who apparently was given it as a gift
回来时收到的礼物
when he returned from world war ii.
-就是这个了  -噢
- And there you have it. - Oh.
这瓶酒现在在哪里
And where is that bottle now?
它以两万六千美金
It was sold for $26,000
卖给了一名叫做杰夫瑞·麦奎根的网络富翁
to an internet millionaire named Jeffrey Mcguigan.
红色的玻璃瓶子
A red glass bottle.
两万六千美金
At 26 grand...
真是个非常昂贵的凶器啊
That is one expensive murder weapon.
你说这家伙是怎么起家的
How did you say this guy made his millions?
网络赌博  拥有五十个站点
Internet gaming. Owns about 50 sites.
这家伙肯花两万六千美金买一瓶威士忌
The guy spent 26k on a bottle of whiskey.
他理应买个更像样的房子啊
He could treat himself to nicer digs.
-他有什么动机  -我只知道
- What's his motivation?  - All I know is that
这是关于那具被弃河的尸体
this is about a body's throw away from the river.
斯皮蒂·旺科臭小子
Speedy Wok my ass.
你不是斯皮蒂·旺科
You're not even Speedy Wok.
我们来这里是为了一件在海根&格瑞姆拍卖行
We're here about a purchase that was made
被购买的物品
at Hagen & Graham's.
杰夫瑞·麦奎根在这里吗
Is there a Jeffrey Mcguigan here?
叫我麦古  这是我出来混的名字  懂吗
I go by Magoo. It's my street name, you know?
-说真的  你就是杰夫瑞·麦奎根  -麦古
- Seriously, you're Jeffrey Mcguigan?  - Magoo.
是的  我在那里买了很多垃圾
And yeah, I've purchased a ton of crap at that place.
进来吧
Come on in.
我们要找的这个"垃圾"  麦古
So this piece of crap we're looking for, Magoo,
是一瓶无价的红瓶苏格兰酒
Is a priceless red bottle of scotch.
不  有标价的  好吧  但那挺好喝的
No, it had a price, all right. But it was pretty tasty.
好喝
Tasty?
你用"好喝"来形容一瓶一百三十五年的佳酿吗
You describe a 135-year-old bottle of scotch as "Tasty"?
我的意思是说混了点麦根啤酒之后挺好喝
I mean, you know, after I mixed in a little rootbeer.
好了  麦古  让我们看看那个瓶子
Yeah, okay, Magoo, let's see that bottle.
你认真的吗  你就这样随便走进我的家
Seriously? You're just gonna walk into my crib
-然后开始指挥我吗  -看起来不在这里
- and start bossing me around?  - Well, I don't see it here.
你不会碰巧将瓶子打破了吧
You didn't happen to break the bottle over... something?
你们来到底有什么事  你知道吗
What is this about? You know, I may have
我在公司上市时  我的确从康奈尔大学退了学
dropped out of cornell when my company went public,
但我仍然知道我的权利
but I still know my rights.
你购买的那瓶酒
That bottle that you purchased
有可能被用来当作凶器了
might have been used to commit murder.
所以除非你想让我宣读你的米兰达权利
So unless you want to learn your miranda rights,
你最好别拖延时间  找出来给我们看看
you better quit stalling and show us where it is.
好的  好的  我没在拖时间
Yeah, okay, cool. I'm not stalling.
-很好  -是的
- Great.  - Yeah.
你要把它丢掉吗
You were throwing it out?
在蓝桶里  循环利用
In the blue bucket. I recycle.
这仍然完好无损
Well, it's still intact.
除非是击打时令玻璃碎片掉落
Unless a sliver of glass came out when it hit--
伙计  没人打架
Man, nobody hit anybody.
是啊  继续将麦根啤酒和上等威士忌
Yes, well, keep mixing rootbeer with fine scotch,
混在一起喝  我都想扁你了
that may change...
好了  卡塞尔  走吧
Okay, Castle. Let's go.
-别说我没提醒你哦  -谢谢
- Just so you know.  - Thank you.
那白痴的小毛孩根本不配
Cretinous little uncultured palate doesn't deserve--
你听到他说什么了吗  麦根啤酒
did you hear what he said? Rootbeer.
要是我年轻个十五岁  我肯定痛扁他
If I was 15 years younger, I'd give that kid such a pinch.
一样的玻璃
Same glass,
但唐尼头上的碎片
but the shard in Donny's head
太大了  不可能是这个瓶子上的
is way too big to have come from this bottle.
就是说这并不是
Which means it can't be
世界上仅存的一瓶
the only remaining bottle in the world.
显然不是
Clearly not.
这就表示我还有机会尝到这佳酿
Which means I still have a shot at getting a taste.
就是说唐尼找到了另一瓶酒
Which means that Donny came across a second bottle.
-没错  在他头上找到了  -好的  那可能里奥
- Yeah, upside his head.  - Okay, so maybe leo
把酒给了亲戚或者朋友
gave a bottle to a relative or a friend,
当唐尼发现这瓶酒的价值之后
and once Donny learned how much it was worth,
他想去找回来
he went after it.
结果酒没拿到  还赔了性命
And got more than he bargained for.
我想我得调查一下里奥了
I think I'm gonna do a little research on Leo,
看看我们能否找到沃克市长
see what we can dig up on Mayor Walker
和他神秘威士忌的资料
and his mystery whiskey.
调查
Research.
我也要调查一下了
I'm gonna do that, too.
没错
Yeah.
这叫边车
It's called the sidecar--
这是禁酒令期间涌现的最好的鸡尾酒
one of the best drinks to come out of the prohibition area.
那个时候  喝酒意味着要暗中进行
A time when getting a drink meant secret doors,
还会和帮派和走私酒的人扯上关系
gangsters, and bootleggers.
噢  里克  我喜欢这个主意
Ooh, Rick, I'm loving this idea.
你知道  城里真是需要一个怀旧的地方
You know, our town could use a throwback joint.
噢  想到完美的名字  "里克美国咖啡屋"
Ooh, perfect name for it-- "Rick's cafe americain."
老妈  这太完美了
Mother, that's perfect.
我在尝试把自己名字弄到酒吧名字里去
I was trying to come up with a bogie reference myself.
可我能想出来的只有  卡塞尔布兰卡
All I could think of was "Castle-blanca."
-我觉得这样太直白了  -没错
- I thought it was a little too on the nose. - Yeah.
我需要喝一杯
I need a drink.
水  马蒂尼酒的做法
H2O, dirty.
一杯自来水
Tap water it is.
那么你的暗黑分身去哪了
So where's your dark shadow?
她跟一些在纽约时装学院认识的朋友出去了
She went out with some people she met at F.I.T.
没邀请我
I was not invited.
我不知道应该高兴还是生气
I don't know whether to be delighted or outraged.
我也是  她维护自我意识很强
Me neither. She's really defensive,
而且她拿所有我在乎的事情开玩笑
and she makes fun of everything that's important to me.
我不断寻找往日格雷西的影子
I keep looking for the Gracie I knew,
-但她已经不在了  -那么
- but she's just not there anymore.  - Well,
你也不是从前那个女孩了
you're not the same girl you were back then either.
你知道吗  或者她只是在
You know, maybe she's just responding
-对你的变化作出反应  -我没变
- to how you've changed.  - I haven't changed.
噢  亲爱的  拜托了  看看你
Oh, darling, please. Look at you.
你长高了  漂亮  优雅
You are tall, beautiful, sophisticated.
你有个迷人的奶奶  还有
You have a glam gram, and...
他  还有个男友
him, and a boyfriend.
你有想过  这些或许让一个来自堪萨斯州的
You know, did it ever occur to you, that might be
-女孩感到有些畏惧吗  -畏惧
- rather intimidating to a girl from Kansas?  - Intimidated?
当我问她的手套在哪里买的
When I asked where she got her gloves,
她说是在我不会去的地方
she said it was a place I wouldn't go to.
你把那话当作是冒犯
Now you took that as an affront,
但她很可能只是在自贬而已
and she was just probably being self-deprecating.
我想有人需要一杯无酒精莫吉托[一种鸡尾酒]
You know what? I think someone needs a virgin mojito.
帮我再拿些薄荷过来  在冰箱里
Go grab me some more mint. It's in the fridge.
-敬你  孩子  -也敬你
- Here's looking at you, kid.  - And you.
你应该事先告诉我你设下了陷阱
You coulda told me you booby-trapped it.
是啊  我就是通过这种方法防止政府和黑帮
Oh, yes. Well, that's just how I protect my stash
发现我的宝物啊
from g-men and mobsters.
-至少你得帮我把它们重装进去  -好
- Mm. At least help me reload them.  - Right.
重装
Reload.
重装[有给枪上膛的意思]
贝克特  我想我知道唐尼是怎么中枪的了
Beckett, I think I know how Donny was shot.
与我一同踏上这看似容易却又危险重重的旅程
Take a trip with me to a simple yet dangerous time...
卡塞尔  鉴证科已经检查过整个地下室了
Castle, C.S.U. already swept through this entire basement,
我们好不容易拿着笔记本躺在了床上
and we were just tucked in with my laptop.
我们
"We"?
乔什和我  他帮我一起调查
Josh and I. He was helping me research.
总之  那个时候禁酒令是明文法令
Anyway, a dangerous time when prohibition was law
走私酒的人则是亡命之徒
and bootleggers the lawless,
通常会采取极端措施
often going to extreme measures
保护他们的"液体财富"
to protect their liquid treasure.
-你能说重点吗  -好的
- Can you get to the point?  - Yes.
你还记得唐尼突然跳出来
You remember when Donny jumped up
从皮卡皮特手中救了安妮吗
and rescued Annie from pick-up Pete?
她说她把钱放到地下室保险箱的时候
She said she completely missed him
完全没有发现他在这
when she was down here doing her safe drop.
当时很晚  她很疲惫
It was late. She was tired.
我知道她的感受
I can relate.
也许他根本就不在那里
Or maybe he wasn't down here at all.
被铅弹击中的墙
Buckshot wall...
正对面的墙
Wall directly opposite.
帮我移一下柜子
Help me move the shelf.
我们究竟想找什么
And what exactly are we hoping to find?
真相  唐尼也想找到真相啊
The truth. The same thing Donny was hoping for.
里奥讲的那些故事
In all the stories that Leo ever told,
这位"酒吧历史学家"
this bar historian,
他有没有可能留给唐尼一个故事呢
what if he saved one story just for Donny?
一个里奥自己也无法证实的故事
A story that Leo himself could never verify
因为直到他死后
because the trapdoor to the basement wasn't discovered
地下室才被人发现
until after he died.
当比利·皮特决定卖掉这间酒吧
When Billy Pitt decided to sell the bar,
而TJ麦克查纳想买下时
and T.J. Mcchucklenuts was going to buy it,
唐尼意识到他必须及时找到真相
Donny realized he had to find out before it was too late.
什么真相
Find what?
唐尼卖掉自己的工会卡  并赌上全部身家
Donny sold his union card and bet his life savings
那个美男詹姆斯  过来
That Beau James-- come.
帮帮我
Help me.
我们动手吧
There we go.
美男詹姆斯的宝藏真的存在
That Beau James' secret stash really existed.
-你有在推吗  -我在推
- are you pushing?  - I am pushing!
好了
Okay.
那是
That's...
哇哦
Wow.
卡塞尔
Oh, Castle.
这是当安妮存钱时唐尼所处之地
This is where Donny was when Annie made the drop.
唐尼拉开这扇门
Donny pulled on this door,
然后哎呦喂  枪走火就中弹了
and blam said the lady.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
湍急的流水声
Rushing water.
如果这水流通到东河
If that water leads to the east river,
那么这里就可能是唐尼遇害的地点
then that's probably where Donny was killed.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我们需要照明  对吧
We're gonna need a light, right?
别得瑟  印第安纳[《夺宝奇兵》主角的名字]
Not so fast, Indy.
我们也需要可呼吸空气  所以
We're also gonna need breathable air, so...
火把多帅啊
Torch would be more fun.
这肯定是老下水道的一部分
This must be a part of the old sewer system.
可能是禁酒令期间的运输地道
Probably used these as access tunnels during prohibition.
真难以置信
It's incredible, isn't it?
是的  除了
Yeah, aside from the fact that it's...
潮湿狭窄  还很黑
damp, cramped, dark,
而且我们很明显踩在老鼠屎上  棒极了
and we are almost certainly walking in rat poop. Awesome.
别忘了CHUDS
Don't forget the C.H.U.D.S.
CHUDS是什么
C.H.U.D.S?
寄居地下的食人者[CHUDS的全称]
Cannibalistic humanoid underground dwellers.
下水道里可不少这些
These sewers are crawling with them.
我还以为你是喜欢
You know, I kind of figured you more
《下水道里的短吻鳄》的那种人
for an "Alligator in the sewer" type of guy.
这里有短吻鳄吗
There's alligators down here?
这是什么
What is this?
看起来像是古旧的通道
This looks like an old passageway
用砖封住了很长时间
that was bricked up a long time ago.
是的  直到唐尼找到这里
Yeah, until Donny got at it.
沃克市长的绰号
Mayor Walker's moniker.
1919年  那是禁酒令开始的时间
"1919"--that's when prohibition started.
史上最棒的时空胶囊
Best time capsule ever.
想想看当唐尼发现里奥的传说是真的
Imagine Donny's joy when he realized
他该多欣喜若狂
that Leo's legends were true.
2万6千美金一瓶  谁还在乎布莱恩中饱私囊
$26,000 a bottle--who cares if Brian was skimming?
这些墙上足有上百瓶威士忌
There's gotta be a hundred bottles of scotch on these walls.
拿一瓶给大家看看
Take one down and pass it around.
住手  那是证据
Hey. That's evidence.
已经拿走很多了
And there's already a lot that's been taken.
都是最近拿的
It's fairly recently, too.
这些瓶子上附着厚厚的灰尘
These bottles are caked with dust,
空余的地方却相对干净
and the empty spaces are relatively clean.
这是谋杀凶器
Here's our murder weapon.
希望上面有指纹
Hopefully with some prints on it.
可能还混着血呢
There's probably blood mixed in there, too...
万一你想尝尝
In case you were thinking of tasting it.
得了  我还不至于饥不择食
Come on. I'm not that desperate.
有人发现了唐尼的宝藏
So someone else finds out about Donny's treasure,
跟踪他到了这里
follows him down here,
吓了他一跳  接着打了起来
surprises him, a fight breaks out,
凶手拿起唯一可用的凶器
and the killer grabs the only weapon available...
给他致命一击
Striking the fatal blow.
看起来我们的凶手
And it looks like our killer
沿着同样的路线把尸体拖出去
dragged the body right back out the same way.
看看这个  一路过来
Look at this, all the way down.
一直拖到这里
And then it travels all the way...
地道里应有尽有
Ah, this tunnel has everything--
威士忌宝藏
Secret scotch vault,
隐蔽的谋杀地点
private murder nook,
便捷的弃尸通道
convenient sewage disposal.
我肯定这水一直流向东河
I bet you this water leads straight to the east river.
这个还很亮
This is fairly bright.
几小时前有人来过
Someone's been here in the past few hours.
警察  不许动
Police! Don't move!
停  纽约警局
Stop! NYPD!
这边  这边
This way. This way.
他去哪了
Where did he go?
他就在我们前面  我听到了
He was right in front of us. I heard him.
这是个死胡同
This is a dead end.
他不可能在我们眼皮底下逃走
He couldn't have gotten past us.
他无路可逃
There is no other way he could've gotten out.
那他是怎么逃走的
So how did he get away?
什么意思  消失
What do you mean, gone?
他明明就在我们前面  接着
He was right there in front of us, and then...
就剩一堵墙了
nothing but a brick wall.
那家伙不可能越过你们
And there's no way this guy could've gotten past you two
偷偷从"老地方"逃走吗
and snuck out through the Old Haunt?
不可能  那里太窄了
No, it was too narrow.
酒保布莱恩和几个常客
Brian the bartender and a handful of regulars
仍在上面
were still upstairs.
他们发誓在我们之前没人出来过
They swear, no one came out before we did.
我们认为爱酒如命的市长
We think that our spirit-loving mayor
不想被人看到他进出
didn't want to be seen going back and forth
最爱的地下酒吧
from his favorite speakeasy,
因此在储藏室修了个后门
So he had a back way entrance built to his stash.
难于察觉  相信我  我们看过了
Hidden from view, and trust me, we looked.
刚刚接到蕾妮的电话
Yo, just got off the phone with Lanie.
证实碎酒瓶上的血迹是唐尼的
She confirms the blood on the broken bottle is Donny's.
这肯定是谋杀凶器
It's definitely our murder weapon.
但我们比对了指纹  还没有找到匹配记录
But we run the prints, and we still came up empty.
在"老地方"或系统中都找不到
No matches to anyone at the Old Haunt or in our system.
花了70年才找到
It took 70 years to find a way
"老地方"下面的地道
down to those tunnels from the Old Haunt,
而凶手却找到另一个入口  怎么找到的
and somehow our killer finds another way in? How?
从地道到东河下水道
There's gotta be another access point
应该还有一个入口
from the tunnel to the east river sewer line.
但官方的下水道地图里却没有显示
But the sewer bureau's map doesn't have anything.
好像联合爱迪生电力公司
It's like Con Ed doesn't
甚至不知道这些地道的存在
even know those tunnels exist.
因为这是现代下水道
That's because these are modern sewer lines.
当新的下水道修建时
Any of the old sewer lines that didn't get patched in
旧的如果利用不上
when the new ones were built,
旧的就会被堵住弃置
they just got bricked up and abandoned.
这就像旧地铁线
That's like old subway lines.
有些整个地铁站在地下
There are whole stations underground
废弃了几十年
no one's seen for decades.
总的来说  我们需要看看旧下水道地图
So basically, we need to take a look at an old sewer map,
一旦找出凶手消失的方向
and once we figure out where our killer disappeared to,
我们也许可以找到另一端的目击证人
we might be able to find some witnesses on the other end.
去找地图吧
Then let's find that map.
这地方也该弄得现代化一点了吧
This place could use a little gentrification,
至少应该弄个复印机吧
at the very least, a copy machine.
这是二战前的档案保管区  卡塞尔
It's the pre-World War II archives section, Castle.
这里一半的东西可能至少七十年都没人动过了吧
Half of this probably hasn't been seen in over 70 years.
1920年的下东区
Lower East Side, 1920.
禁酒令差不多就是这个时候开始实施的
That's about when prohibition was getting started.
你看那个年代
Aw, you see how much nicer
这个地区比现在好多少呀
the neighborhood was back then?
你觉得那个小格子会不会
You think that little box there
-就是"老地方"  -没错  位置是没错
- might be the Old Haunt?  - Yeah, that's where it would be,
那时候它还是所妓院呢
not long after its bordello phase.
你还能见到有人穿着吊袜带呢
You can still see the little garter belts.
这下面有条污水管道
Okay, there's a sewer line
新的地图上是没有标出来的
running under it that wasn't on the newer map,
所以这肯定就是我们要找的地道
so that's gotta be our tunnel.
那也就是说沃克的威士忌应该就藏在这
Which would put Walker's whiskey right about here.
他可以去酒窖拿上一瓶
A man could grab himself a bottle, come and go
来去都不会被人看见
without ever being seen.
但是从哪来回  起点是哪
But come and go from where? Where did he start from?
这里是地道的终点  我们的凶手也是在这消失的
Here's where our tunnel ends and our killer vanished.
这一点一共连接着
There's one, two, three sewer lines
一  二  三条污水管道呢
that branch off from that point.
凶手可能选择了任意一条
Any of which our killer could've accessed
从我们眼前逃走
to get away from us.
所以如果我们可以找出
So if we can figure out
这三条污水管道通向哪里
exactly where the three sewers end,
我们就可以申请法庭传票  收集凶手
we can subpoena traffic cams
逃跑的那个时间段里所有的交通摄像
around the time the killer got away,
也许能确认凶手的身份
maybe get an I.D.
也许根本用不着那么麻烦
Or maybe we won't need any of that.
你说七十多年来都没人
You said no one has laid eyes on these maps
看过这些地图
in over 70 years,
可是根据这张借书卡
only it says here,
两个星期前才有人借出过这张地图
someone checked this one out just two weeks ago.
而且我以美男詹姆斯的威士忌打赌
And I'll bet a bottle of Beau James' whiskey
有人跟咱俩一样  想要找到一条
that someone was trying to make their way
通往市长藏酒室的路
back to the mayor's stash, just like we are.
第一次  第二次[拍卖术语]
Going once, going twice...
此项物品由坐在后面的那位先生收购
Sold to the gentleman in the back.
接下来  是一瓶1955年的
Next up, we have a marvelous
雷斯蒂沃城堡酒庄的白葡萄酒
1955 Chateau Restivo Blanc,
竞拍起价为一千二百美金
and we'll start the bidding at $1,200.
有人出价一千二百美金吗
Do I hear $1,200?
一千二百美金  有一千两百五十美金吗
There's $1,200. Do I hear $1,250?
一千两百五十美金  有人出价一千三吗
$1,250 there. $1,300?
一千三
13 --
后面有人出价一千三百美金
$1,300 in the back.
有一千三百五十美金吗
Do I hear $1,350?
一千三百五
$1,350...
一千三百五十
有人出价
Do I hear...
一千四百
14 --
这只是一场唐尼信错了人而导致的悲剧
It's just a sad case of Donny trusting the wrong guy.
他告诉海斯勒他找到了美男詹姆斯的藏酒
He told Heisler about the Beau James' stash,
-海斯勒就起了贪念  -他说服唐尼
- and Heisler got greedy.  - He convinced Donny
如果他把这些威士忌分开
that the whiskey would fetch a better price
一次只卖一瓶  价格会抬得更高
if he sold it a bottle at a time,
于是唐尼就没动剩下的藏酒
so Donny left the stash where he found it.
这给了海斯勒充裕的时间
And that gave Heisler
去寻找藏酒
enough time to figure out where it was hidden.
当唐尼在酒窖里将海斯勒抓了个现行
When Donny caught him in the vault,
海斯勒惊慌失措地用酒瓶打了他
Heisler panicked, hit him with a bottle.
我们搞清楚
Yo. We figured out
海斯勒是怎么从你们眼前消失的了
how Heisler disappeared on you in the tunnel.
密道
Secret passageway.
差不多是这么回事
Basically.
他有一个秘密入口  是只能从
He had a hidden entrance that could only be opened
外边打开的  鉴证组发现
from the other side. Now CSU followed it
这条通道从废弃的污水管一直通往地道
from the street to the abandoned sewer to the tunnel,
就像沃克市长计划的一样
just like Mayor Walker had drew it up.
这是海斯勒还没来得及
Here's, uh, three cases
卖的三箱酒
that Heisler hadn't gotten around to selling yet.
两万六一瓶的话
At 26 g's a pop,
这里总共也值差不多一百万美金了
you're looking at just under a cool million.
让我摸摸  我怎么才能买上一瓶
I just -- how might I acquire one of these for myself?
卡塞尔  我跟你说过  这些是证据
Castle, I told you, they're evidence.
没错  但是谁说得准今天的证据
Yes, but who's to say that today's evidence
-不会成为明天的睡前饮料呢  -我说得准
- can't be tomorrow's nightcap?  - That would be me.
我相信我们肯定得花上几个月的时间
I'm sure it'll be a few months before we can figure out
才能确定这些酒到底归谁所有
where this and the rest of this stuff belongs.
我是蒙哥马利
Montgomery. Yeah.
真漂亮呀
Look at you.
酷吧  格雷西带我去一间
Isn't it cool? Gracie took me shopping
我根本没听说过的店买衣服
in this place I never even knew existed,
那间店离这只有一街之隔
and it's right down the street from here.
那卖的东西很棒  她的眼光也超好
They had the greatest stuff. She has a really good eye.
是阿丽克西斯穿什么都好看
Well, Alexis looks good in everything.
很高兴见到你们俩又重归于好了
I'm glad you two reconnected.
我们只是要花点时间重新了解对方
We just had to get to know the new uses.
我们俩都不再是十岁的小屁孩了
Neither of us are 10 anymore.
谢谢你让我住在卡塞尔豪宅
Thanks for letting me crash at Chez Castle.
让我回想起小时候不知生活艰辛的
It reminded me of the good ol' days
那些美好的时光  你明白吗
before life got too real, you know?
我明白
I do know.
我陪她走去火车站
I'm gonna walk her to the train.
拜拜
Bye.
奶奶在楼下等着呢
Gram's waiting downstairs.
谢谢你提前给我打预防针
Thanks for the warning.
我还记得我那个阶段呢
Wow. I remember that phase.
我差不多就是那个时候纹的身
That's about when I got my tattoo.
你还有纹身呢  在
You've got a tattoo? Well, on --
在哪
I...where?
刚跟地方检察官通过电话  卡塞尔
Just heard from the DA, Castle.
既然这些酒
Apparently since all of these bottles
曾经归我们的前任市长
used to belong to Beau James,
美男詹姆斯所有
and he used to be our mayor,
她建议现在将这些酒归为市有财产
it's her opinion that they're owned by the city.
但是她说  如果你愿意慷慨解囊
But she says if you're willing to make a generous donation
赞助纽约警局的孤儿寡母基金的话
to the NYPD widows and orphans' fund,
就送你一瓶美男詹姆斯的上好威士忌
you can have one of Beau James' best for your very own.
这是你提前收到的圣诞大礼了
This is early christmas, baby.
我  可以吗
I...may...
我真没想到会如此幸运
I was not expecting this.
-你在哭吗  -是的
- Are you crying?  - Yes.
我激动地不知道该说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
说"让我拿支票簿来写张支票"就行了
Try "Let me get my checkbook".
当然  这是当然了  但是我
Yes, of course. Of course. But I...
我不能一个人独占  我要跟你们一起分享
I will only accept this if you all share it with me.
-就等你这句话了  -不行
- Twist my arm.  - No.
在这不行  要去"老地方"
Not here. Um, at the Old Haunt.
我们要敬唐尼和他的家人一杯
We will toast to Donny with his family.
对哦  说起那个地方
Yeah, well, what ab -- what about that place?
"老地方"将会被如何处置呢
What happens to the Old Haunt?
那里将会被银行收回  也就是说
It's gonna go back to the bank, which means that
TJ麦克查纳又要再次竞价了
T.J. Mcchucklenuts is gonna get another shot at it.
用不着担心"老地方"
Oh, I wouldn't worry about the Old Haunt.
你把它买下了  对吧
You bought it, didn't you?
你跟我们一起来吗
So are you joining us?
我是想去
You know, I'd love to.
但是现在太晚了  我还有很多文件要处理呢
It's late, and I've got a lot of paperwork.
现在是周六晚上九点耶
It's 9:00 on a Saturday.
已经九点十五了
9:15, actually.
*常客们又拥了进来*[比利·乔的《钢琴师》]
*The regular crowd shuffles in*
*我身边坐着个老头*
*There's an old man sitting next to me*
*狂爱他的*
*Making love*
*金汤力*[汤力水和琴酒兑在一起的鸡尾酒]
*To his tonic and gin*
*他说"孩子  能给我弹上一首老曲吗"*
*He said, "Son, can you play me a memory*
*我也不记得曲调了*
*I'm not really sure how it goes*
*但我知道它悲伤又甜美*
*But it's sad and it's sweet*
*我年轻的时候*
*And I knew it complete*
*还完整地记着这首歌呢*
*When I wore a younger man's clothes*
*给我们唱首歌吧  你是钢琴师*
*Sing us a song, you're the piano man*
*今晚给我们唱首歌吧*
*Sing us a song tonight*
*我们大家都想听首歌*
*Well, we're all in the mood for a melody*
*你让我们激情澎湃*
*And you got us feeling all right*